Finding Aid for Engineering Research Center for Reconfigurable Machining Systems (University of Michigan) records, 1995-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Engineering Research Center for Reconfigurable Machining Systems (University of Michigan) records 1995-2007
University of Michigan. Engineering Research Center for Reconfigurable Machining Systems.
2008124 Bimu 2
In 1996, the National Science Foundation awarded a grant to the University of Michigan College of Engineering to establish an Engineering Research Center for Reconfigurable Machining Systems. Records include annual reports, background, proposals, lists of staff and corporate partners, and publications.
2 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were received from the Engineering Research Center for Reconfigurable Machining Systems (Donor No. 1884 ) in July 2008.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The Engineering Research Center for Reconfigurable Machining Systems records are open for research without restriction.
In 1996, the University of Michigan College of Engineering received a grant from the National Science Foundation (NSF) to create an NSF Engineering Research Center (ERC) for Reconfigurable Machining Systems (RMS). A Reconfigurable Manufacturing System is one designed at the outset for rapid change in its structure, as well as its hardware and software components, in order to accommodate rapid adjustments of production capacity and functionality. The University of Michigan ERC/RMS, one of 22 in the nation in 2006, worked to develop an evolving factory, containing an RMS, to be altered as needed.
The ERC's research is organized into three main clusters: System-Level Design, Machine/Control Design; and Calibration and Ramp Up. In addition, the Center is founded on five discipline-based research thrust areas: system design and integration, software architecture and information, measurement and controls, mechanical design, and processes and tooling. The Center also engages in educational and outreach programs aimed at K-12 and college students.
The Center's participants include approximately 25 faculty members, 10 research scientists, and 40 graduate and 40 undergraduate students from the College of Engineering and the School of Business Administration. Thirty industrial companies, including suppliers, control vendors and software companies, aided in the founding of the Center, have participated in its projects, and continue to support the Center. Payment of an annual fee allows them access to the intellectual property generated by the program's research.
The records of the Engineering Research Center for Reconfigurable Machining Systems provide documentation of the program from its proposal stages through its operation as a major National Science Foundation Engineering Research Center.
The records are arranged into four series: Annual Reports, Topical Files, Publications, and CD-Roms. The Annual Reports are arranged chronologically and document by year the activities and progress of the Center between 1996 and 2007. The Publications series is comprised of published information by and about the Center, while the Topical Files contains documents arranged by topic, with special emphasis on program participants and the original budget and proposal submitted to NSF. The CD-Roms series contains CD-Roms on the following topics: ERC/RMS patents, CIRP 2nd International Conference on Reconfigurable Manufacturing, and the Reconfigurable Factory Testbed operated by the Center.
Subjects:
Computer integrated manufacturing systems.; Manufacturing processes.; Mechanical engineering.; National Science Foundation (U.S.). Engineering Research Centers Program.
- Annual Reports
  - 1997, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - 1998, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - 1999, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - 2000, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - 2001, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - 2002, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - 2003, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - 2004, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - 2005, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - 2006, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - 11 Years Retrospective 2007 (Box 2)
- Publications
  - "Reconfigurable Manufacturing Systems--An Overview," 2002 (Box 2)
  - "Reconfigurable Manufacturing Systems--An Overview," 2003 (Box 2)
  - "Report to Industry" 2004 (Box 2)
  - "Innovations and Inventions, 1999-2005" (2005) (Box 2)
  - "Engineering Research Centers 2005-2006 Program Report" (Box 2)
- Topical Files
  - Background (Box 2)
  - Book of Proposals 1996 (Box 2)
  - Budget 1996 (Box 2)
  - Education Strategic Plan 1999 (Box 2)
  - List of Corporate Partners (Box 2)
  - Original Proposal 1995 (Box 2)
  - Response to Minor Concerns 1999 (Box 2)
  - Site Visits (Box 2)
  - Student Roster 1997 (Box 2)
  - Student Resume Book 2002 (Box 2)
  - Student Handbook 1999 (Box 2)
  - Wee Wizards materials 2005 (Box 2)
- CD-Roms
  - ERC/RMS Patents, 1 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 2)
  - CIRP 2nd International Conference on Reconfigurable Manufacturing August 20-21, 2003, 1 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 2)
  - ERC/RMS Reconfigurable Factory Testbed, 1 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 2)